<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE nox:page PUBLIC "-//dtischer//DTD page 1.0//EN" "../../dtd/page.dtd">
<nox:page xmlns:nox="http://dtischer.free.fr/nox" title="Career : OHIM" type="static">
  <nox:section>
    <h1>2003 - 2013 : OHIM - Alicante</h1>
    <p>
      <a href="http://oami.europa.eu/" rel="external" shape="rect">http://oami.europa.eu/</a>
    </p>
    <p>
      <img alt="OHIM" class="right" src="../images/site/experience/ohim.jpg" />The Office for
      Harmonization in the Internal Market (OHIM) registers Community <strong>Trade Marks</strong>
      and Community <strong>Designs</strong>.</p>
    <p>The Community Trade Mark and the Community Design both grant their proprietors a uniform
      right valid in all Member States of the European Union by means of one procedural system,
      which is implemented in two IT-systems: EUROMARC and EURODESIGN.</p>
    <p>EURODESIGN is a custom-made software tool used by the Office to examine Community Designs
      (RCD) applications. It also serves as the Register of RCDs (held exclusively in electronic
      form) and is a web-based technology program.</p>
    <p>A registered Community design (RCD) is an exclusive right for the outward appearance of a
      product or part of it. A RCD initially has a life of five years that can be renewed in blocks
      of five years up to a maximum of 25 years. The fact that the right is registered constitutes
      an important feature as it gives it greater certainty and solidity in case of
      infringements.</p>
  </nox:section>
  <nox:section>
    <p>
      <a href="http://www.infeurope.lu/" rel="external">Infeurope</a> acted as IT service provider
      from 2001 to 2007 on the maintenance and evolution of EUROMARC and was in parallel charged
      with the process of building the new system EURODESIGN. We were responsible for the
      development, integration and testing of EURODESIGN.</p>
    <p>Since October 2004, I moved to Alicante to work in the client's premises, a highly
      international and multicultural environment. Being on site, I had frequent contacts with
      end-users. I participated in the Java/J2EE development, especially for the integration with
      other modules and writing test cases.</p>
  </nox:section>
</nox:page>
