<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE nox:page PUBLIC "-//dtischer//DTD page 1.0//EN" "../../dtd/page.dtd">
<nox:page xmlns:nox="http://dtischer.free.fr/nox" title="Career : infeurope S.A. - SIMAP"
  type="static">
  <nox:section>
    <h1>European Commission - SIMAP</h1>
    <p>03/1998 - 12/1999, infeurope S.A. Luxembourg, Brussels (Belgium), Murcia (Spain)<br />
      <a href="http://simap.eu.int/" rel="external" shape="rect">http://simap.eu.int/</a>
    </p>
    <p>Design and full implementation of the Système d'Information pour les Marchés Publics (SIMAP)
      under the direction of the European Commission. This project was very large and we used a
      broad range of tools to achieve the impossible, in a context of legal and political tension.
      For my first Internet project, it was one of the most rewarding as I learned a lot from the
      mistakes that have been made.</p>
    <h2>Background</h2>
    <p>SIMAP is an initiative of the <a href="http://europa.eu" rel="external" shape="rect">European
        Commission</a> to greatly increase the efficiency of public purchasing, through the use of
      information and communication technologies. It was launched in 1994, together with 15 Member
      States as well as some of the EU's European trading partners.</p>
    <p>At the February 1995 summit on the Information Society, the leaders of the G7 nations decided
      that electronic tendering should be developed as a priority application for the new
      information superhighways. In a few years the whole procurement process could take place
      electronically, from internal planning through electronic tendering to invoicing and payment,
      offering enormous savings in time and increasing efficiency.</p>
    <p>
      <a class="image" href="../doc/career/simap_brochure.pdf">
        <img alt="SIMAP Brochure" src="../images/experience/thumbs/simap_brochure.png" />
      </a> &#160;&#160;&#160; <a class="image" href="../doc/career/simap_provedores.pdf">
        <img alt="SIMAP Leaflet1" src="../images/experience/thumbs/simap_provedores.png" />
      </a> &#160;&#160;&#160; <a class="image" href="../doc/career/simap_adjudicadores.pdf">
        <img alt="SIMAP Leaflet2" src="../images/experience/thumbs/simap_adjudicadores.png" />
      </a> &#160;&#160;&#160; <a class="image" href="../doc/career/simap_murcia.pdf">
        <img alt="SIMAP in Murcia" src="../images/experience/thumbs/simap_murcia.png" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <h2>Functional overview</h2>
    <p>The development was meant to replace two existing pilot projects: a PC-based software with a
      graphical user interface to control data entry of standard public procurement forms, and a
      search and retrieval tool to disseminate the procurement information.</p>
    <p>The Commission then decided to make SIMAP available generally through Internet, redesigning
      the forms to be used with the latest technology available. Again, the project divides into two
      parts :</p>
    <ul>
      <li>
        <b>Notification</b>: The Purchaser Point allows purchasers (awarding authorities) to enter
        their procurement notices for publication in the Official Journal Supplement using online
        forms.</li>
      <li>
        <b>Dissemination</b>: You can search through the <em>Internet Procurement Database</em> for
        general information on public procurement collected from selected Public Procurement sites,
        through the <em>Procurement Opportunities Database</em> for information on specific
        procurement opportunities currently available, and through the <em>Purchaser Profiles</em>
        to see what different organizations are buying, plan to buy or have bought in the past.</li>
    </ul>
    <h2>Technical overview</h2>
    <p class="right">
      <a class="image" href="../images/experience/exp_simap.png" rel="external" shape="rect">
        <img alt="SIMAP       Architecture" class="right" height="150"
          src="../images/experience/thumbs/exp_simap.png" width="100" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <p>The two parts of the project have been developed separately.</p>
    <ol>
      <li>
        <b>Notification</b>: <ul>
          <li>Form based workflow implemented with Java servlets and a custom designed MVC pattern
            for dealing with multilingual (Unicode - UTF8) data;</li>
          <li>A complex mapping required a separate MS Access database to capture the specification
            and generate more than 400 templates;</li>
          <li>Extensive use of Javascript to provide cross-browser dynamic HTML;</li>
          <li>Authentication is made through an LDAP Database that synchronizes user profiles with
            the main Oracle database;</li>
          <li>After processing, the data is exported to the SEI (Système Editorial Informatisé) in
            SGML. Later, an XML gateway is added.</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
      <li>
        <b>Dissemination</b>: Java applets and Perl CGI scripts retrieve information on procurement
        opportunities through a multi criteria search engine.</li>
    </ol>
    <p>Besides this, we developed a wealth of utilities, such as a translation tool in PHP/MySQL, a
      statistical module and many scripts.</p>
    <h2>Software used for the project</h2>
    <table class="preformat">
      <thead>
        <tr>
          <th colspan="1" id="th05DDC4B00000" rowspan="1">Task</th>
          <th colspan="1" id="th05DDC4B00001" rowspan="1">Software</th>
        </tr>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td class="tablesubheader1" colspan="4" headers="th05DDC4B00000" rowspan="1"> </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td colspan="1" headers="th05DDC4B00000" rowspan="1">Programming languages</td>
          <td colspan="1" headers="th05DDC4B00001" rowspan="1">Java JDK 1.1 and 1.2, Java Applets
            and Servlets, JDBC, SQLJ, Perl 5, Javascript (DHTML), PHP 3, XML, Omnimark, Emacs</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td colspan="1" headers="th05DDC4B00000" rowspan="1">Web servers and database</td>
          <td colspan="1" headers="th05DDC4B00001" rowspan="1">Netscape Suitespot 3.5.1, JRun, WAI
            CoolRunner (Servlet Engine) Oracle 7 &amp; 8, Microsoft Access 2000, MySQL</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td colspan="1" headers="th05DDC4B00000" rowspan="1">Development platform</td>
          <td colspan="1" headers="th05DDC4B00001" rowspan="1">Solaris 2.5.1, SuSE Linux, Windows NT
            4</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </nox:section>
</nox:page>
