<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE nox:page PUBLIC "-//dtischer//DTD page 1.0//EN" "../../dtd/page.dtd">
<nox:page xmlns:nox="http://dtischer.free.fr/nox" title="Career : infeurope S.A. - TED Alert"
  type="static">
  <nox:section>
    <h1>Euroscript - TED ALERT</h1>
    <p>01/2000 - 04/2000, infeurope S.A. Luxembourg<br />
      <a href="http://www.tenders.com/" rel="external" shape="rect">http://www.tenders.com/</a>
    </p>
    <p>Project lead (3 developers) for the technical analysis and modelling of the TED ALERT pilot
      project. Software architecture planning, sizing and performance analysis for data volumes
      exceeding 80 gigabytes per year. Evaluation of Intershop Enfinity as gateway for paying
      services such as translation and advertising.</p>
    <p>The customer was a company of the <a href="http://www.holtzbrinck.com/" rel="external"
        shape="rect">Holtzbrinck group</a> specialized in translation services : <a
        href="http://www.euroscript.com/" rel="external" shape="rect">Euroscript</a>. At the time,
      infeurope was owned partly by the <a href="http://www.sol.de/" rel="external" shape="rect"
        >Saarbrucker Zeitung</a> who is running TED and is also part of the Holtzbrinck Group. But
      due to lack of resources and political divergences, the project was abandoned.</p>
    <p>Nevertheless, it appears that <a href="http://www.primesphere.com/" rel="external"
        shape="rect">Primesphere</a> carried out most of the functionalities of this project (see
      link on top).</p>
    <h2>Background</h2>
    <p>TED (Tenders Electronic Daily) is the online version of the Supplement S of the Official
      Journal, produced by the Office for Official Publications of the European Communities. TED
      provides information on public contracts for works, supplies and services from all Member
      States of the European Union. Invitations to tender are published in all the 11 official EU
      languages.</p>
    <p>The TED Alert Service is based on an automatic offline distribution service by fax or e-mail
      of public tenders coming from TED. The mission statement is becoming and being perceived as
      the Nr. 1 provider of information in the procurement (Public and Corporate) market place.</p>
    <h2>Functional overview</h2>
    <p class="right">
      <a class="image" href="../images/site/experience/exp_ted.png" rel="external" shape="rect">
        <img alt="TED       Workflow" class="right" height="122"
          src="../images/site/experience/thumbs/exp_ted.png" width="167" />
      </a>
    </p>
    <p>Original notices (about 600 daily) will be imported and indexed with their summary
      translations in the 11 EU languages.</p>
    <p>The Web service will provide daily alerts, newsletters and a business and competition watch
      database. Users can set up custom search profiles based on <acronym
        title="Common Procurement Vocabulary">CPV</acronym> codes. On the other side, advertiser
      action profiles will match those criteria, therefore reaching the right users.</p>
    <p>In addition, high quality translation and human help support services are available.</p>
    <h2>Software used for the project</h2>
    <table class="preformat">
      <thead>
        <tr>
          <th colspan="1" id="th0D01EF500000" rowspan="1">Task</th>
          <th colspan="1" id="th0D01EF500001" rowspan="1">Software</th>
        </tr>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
        <tr>
          <td class="tablesubheader1" colspan="4" headers="th0D01EF500000" rowspan="1"> </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td colspan="1" headers="th0D01EF500000" rowspan="1">Project Management</td>
          <td colspan="1" headers="th0D01EF500001" rowspan="1">Microsoft Project 98, Microsoft
            Excel, Visio</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td colspan="1" headers="th0D01EF500000" rowspan="1">Portal design</td>
          <td colspan="1" headers="th0D01EF500001" rowspan="1">Photoshop, Dreamweaver</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td colspan="1" headers="th0D01EF500000" rowspan="1">Application servers and database</td>
          <td colspan="1" headers="th0D01EF500001" rowspan="1">Intershop Enfinity, Oracle 8</td>
        </tr>
      </tbody>
    </table>
  </nox:section>
</nox:page>
