<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE nox:page PUBLIC "-//dtischer//DTD page 1.0//EN" "../../dtd/page.dtd">
<nox:page xmlns:nox="http://dtischer.free.fr/nox" title="Projects : Nox" type="static">
    <nox:section>
        <h1>Nox Framework</h1>
        <p>Nox is a free XML Content Management System (CMS) for creating static web sites (offline
            generation). It has limited functionality, but is quite flexible for those who have
            XSLT+CSS knowledge.</p>
        <p>The framework is based on libxml2. Pages are written in XML and transformed to XHTML 1.0
            via XSLT stylesheets.</p>
        <p>Nox was started in 2002 as <b>xproc</b> but in 2005 the W3C announced the launch of the
                <a href="http://www.xproc.org/" shape="rect">XML Processing Model Working Group</a>,
            which unfortunately was also called XProc.</p>
        <h2>Features</h2>
        <ul>
            <li>Based on open standards such as XML, XSLT and CSS</li>
            <li>Content (XML) is separated from presentation (XSLT, CSS)</li>
            <li>Generates well-formed XHTML 1.0</li>
            <li>Flexible two level menu structure</li>
            <li>Multi-language support</li>
            <li>Compiles only modified source files</li>
        </ul>
        <h2>Limitations</h2>
        <ul>
            <li>Editing well-formed XML is not straigthforward (you need a good editor)</li>
            <li>XML / XSLT knowledge is required to modify structural page layout</li>
            <li>There are a few constraints to embed scripting (PHP, JavaScript) into XML</li>
            <li>The process is batch based, it does not manage concurrency, user rights and
                versioning.</li>
            <li>Link validity is not checked at compile time</li>
            <li>Modifying the main menu requires layout fix (preferred.css: #topnav a.nav)</li>
            <li>XIncludes are not dependency checked (requires -f to force rebuild).</li>
            <li>You can only specify one extra file for dependency check (usually
                    <code>menu.xi</code>)</li>
            <li>No locking mechanism for editing pages in Cocoon (it's a single user CMS)</li>
        </ul>
        <h2>Extensions</h2>
        <ul>
            <li>WYSIWYG content editor (Nox-Cocoon)</li>
            <li>PHP search engine and link checker (XTS)</li>
        </ul>
    </nox:section>
</nox:page>
